simplegreensmoothies.com 2018-11-18

# Privacy Policy - Simple Green Smoothies

_Effective Date: May 21, 2018   _

At Simple Green Smoothies, LLC (“Simple Green Smoothies”) we are committed to respecting your privacy choices and being transparent about what information we collect from you and how we use that information. We do not share, sell, license, trade, or rent your personal information to others except in the ways disclosed in this Privacy Policy.

Our Privacy Policy explains:

  * **Why** we collect personally identifiable information;
  * **What** personally identifiable information we collect;
  * **How** we use that information, including how the information is stored and whether we share the information with third parties; and
  * **Your choices** regarding our collection, use, and distribution of that information.

## Does Simple Green Smoothies’ Privacy Policy Apply To Me?

By accessing or using Simple Green Smoothies’ services (“Services”), such as accessing or using information on our website located at [https://simplegreensmoothies.com](https://simplegreensmoothies.com/) (“Site”) or in our e-mailed newsletter, or by downloading or accessing our digital products available on the Site, like our eBooks, for example (“Digital Products”), you accept and agree to the terms of our Privacy Policy. By submitting personal information to our Site in order to gain access to, purchase, or use our Services, Digital Products, or other features of our Site, such as a promotion, contest, giveaway, or sweepstakes on our Site, you accept and agree to the terms of our Privacy Policy and expressly consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

Simple Green Smoothies’ Privacy Policy DOES NOT apply to any information that you submit in a public comment on the Site or to information that you may share on any of Simple Green Smoothies’ social media properties, such as information you share in a comment, like or post on Simple Green Smoothies’ Facebook page, in comments or likes on Simple Green Smoothies’ Instagram posts, or in a Twitter exchange with Simple Green Smoothies. You do not have an expectation of privacy in the information you reveal in a public comment on our Site or in your interactions on any of Simple Green Smoothies’ social media platforms. We are not responsible for any information that you submit to or via a third party (such as Facebook, when you post to, comment on, or like material on the Simple Green Smoothies Facebook Page, for example) or in a public comment on Simple Green Smoothies’ Site.

## What Information Does Simple Green Smoothies Collect?

Simple Green Smoothies collects two types of information from you: personally identifiable information (e.g., information that can be used to identify you specifically, such as your name, e-mail address, billing address, telephone number, credit card information, etc.) and non-personally identifiable information (e.g., information that reasonably could not be linked to or associated with you or aggregated anonymous data, etc.).

**Newsletter Subscription**

When you subscribe to our newsletter, we collect the name and e-mail address that you submit to our newsletter subscription form.

**Challenge Signup**

When you sign up to participate in our free or paid challenges, we collect the name and e-mail address that you submit to our challenge signup form. We give you the option to share more about yourself in an effort to curate content for you, but it’s completely optional.

**Digital Product Download**

When you purchase one of our Digital Products, we collect your name, e-mail address, credit card information, and billing address through PayPal or Authorize.net. When you purchase a free Digital Product, we only collect your name and e-mail address.

**Physical Product Purchase**

When you purchase one of our physical products (books, totes, powders, etc), we collect your name, e-mail address, shipping address, credit card information, and billing address through PayPal or WePay.com.

**Promotions**

If you participate in a Simple Green Smoothies promotion like a giveaway, contest, or sweepstakes, we collect and store the name and e-mail address you submit to enter the promotion.

**Surveys**

If you participate in a Simple Green Smoothies survey, we may collect your name and e-mail address in connection with that survey, as well as the information you agree to submit in the survey.

###### EMAIL INFORMATION

If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received online, mail, and telephone. This also applies when you register for our website, sign up through any of our forms using your email address or make a purchase on this site. For further information see the email policies below.

###### EMAIL POLICIES

We are committed to keeping your e-mail address confidential. We do not sell, rent, or lease our subscription lists to third parties, and will not disclose your email address to any third parties except as allowed in the section titled Disclosure of Your Information.

We will maintain the information you send via e-mail in accordance with applicable federal law.

In compliance with the CAN-SPAM Act, all e-mails sent from our organization will clearly state who the e-mail is from and provide clear information on how to contact the sender. In addition, all e-mail messages will also contain concise information on how to remove yourself from our mailing list so that you receive no further e-mail communication from us.

Our emails provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners by reading the unsubscribe instructions located at the bottom of any e-mail they receive from us at anytime.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials may opt-out of receiving these communications by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the e-mail.

###### HOW AND WHY WE COLLECT INFORMATION

The Company collects your information in order to record and support your participation in the activities you select. If you register to download a book or resources, sign up for our newsletter, and/or purchase a product from us, we collect your information. We use this information to track your preferences and to keep you informed about the products and services you have selected to receive and any related products and/or services. As a visitor to this Website, you can engage in most activities without providing any personal information. It is only when you seek to download resources and/or register for services that you are required to provide information.

If you are outside the European Union and opt to receive any free resources, challenges, participate in any free training programs, register for a webinar, register for a live event, register for a seminar, or purchase any products sold by the Company on this Website, we will automatically enroll ​you to receive our free email newsletter. If you do not wish to receive this newsletter, you can unsubscribe anytime. We include an “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of every email we send. If you ever have trouble unsubscribing, you can send an email to hello@simplegreensmoothies.com requesting to unsubscribe from future emails.

If you are in the European Union and opt to receive any free resources, participate in any free training programs, register for a webinar, register for a live event, register for a seminar, or purchase any products sold by the Company on this Website, we will only enroll ​you to receive our free email newsletter if you affirmatively consent to it. If you do not wish to receive this newsletter, you can unsubscribe anytime. We include an “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of every email we send. If you ever have trouble unsubscribing, you can send an email to hello@simplegreensmoothies.com requesting to unsubscribe from future emails.

## Does Your Site Use Cookies?

Our website uses cookies in order to deliver a better experience for you. For example, if you log in to our site, we may be able to personalize your experience by recognizing your name when you return to the site, save your login and/or password, or enable your shopping cart function. Our newsletters and e-mail messages may use cookies to measure the effectiveness of our marketing (e.g., to track clicks on links in our e-mails/newsletters) or we may use cookies to determine the number of times Site visitors have accessed a particular area on the site. Most web browsers have a function that allows you to delete existing cookies on your device or you can set your browser options so that your device does not receive or accept cookies.

## Third Party Analytics

We use Google Analytics, which uses cookies and collects aggregate data from our website visitors, such as which areas of our Site receive the most traffic, how often visitors go to a particular page and the duration of their visits, general geographical location information, or the source of referred traffic to our Site (e.g., visits via search engine search or Pinterest, etc.). Google Analytics also collects the IP address assigned to you on the date of your visit. We do not separately aggregate or store your IP address with any of your personal information outside of the data we access in Google Analytics. Learn more about Google Analytics, including its use of cookies [here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage).

We also use Facebook Tracking Pixels to help us target our marketing campaigns to fit you best.

By using the website, you are consenting to the use of cookies to retain session information for the purposes listed above. This information is held in your web browser and is removed at the end of your session.

The personal information we collect and hold via Tracking software is the following: –

  * Browser used (Bing, Chrome, Internet Explorer etc.)
  * Location (based on IP address)
  * Gender
  * Age group
  * Site searches
  * Device(s) used
  * Frequency on Site
  * Session duration (time spent on the site)
  * Page(s) visited
  * Page session duration (time spent on specific page)
  * Web Surfing Behaviours

We currently use the following companies that may process your personal data through website usage: Facebook, Google, Intercom, and InfusionSoft.

## What Does Simple Green Smoothies Do With My Information?

Non-Personally Identifiable Information

We use non-personally identifiable information, like aggregate data about the most visited Site pages or the duration of a certain Site page’s visits from Google Analytics that is not tied to any specific Site user, to maintain, improve, and protect our Site and our product and service offerings.

Personally Identifiable Information

When you sign up for our newsletter or sign up to participate in a green smoothie challenge, we use the name and e-mail address that you provide to subscribe you to our newsletter or our green smoothie challenge e-mail list, in order to send you the newsletter or e-mails. We store the name and e-mail address you provide in an SSL encrypted database.

When you enter a promotion on our Site, we use the information you submit to us to administer the promotion (e.g., enter you into the promotion, notify you if you are a winner, and send you your prize). We store the name and e-mail address you provide in an SSL encrypted database. If the prize for the promotion is administered by a third party, we may provide your name and e-mail address to that third party if you are one of the winners of a promotion. Please read the rules of any promotion prior to entering any giveaway, contest, or sweepstakes.

When you purchase a Digital Product, we use the personal information you provide to process the transaction, deliver the purchased Digital Product(s), and to provide customer service as necessary. We store this information in an SSL encrypted database.

## Does Simple Green Smoothies Share My Personal Information With Third Parties?

There are some instances in which Simple Green Smoothies may share your personal information.

We may disclose your personal information without your consent when we have a good faith belief that we are required to release the information pursuant to any applicable law, regulation, court order, or legal process.

We may also disclose or use your personal information in order to enforce our Terms of Use and/or Privacy Policy, including disclosure or use to investigate potential violations of our Terms of Use and/or Privacy Policy and to detect, prevent, or address fraud, security, or technical issues.

In the event that Simple Green Smoothies merges with a third party, or in the event that all or substantially all of Simple Green Smoothies’ assets are acquired by a third party, your personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information may be shared with, transferred to and/or used by such third party. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy preferences are followed and provide you with notice before your personal information becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

## Do You Collect Children’s Information?

Our Site and our Digital Products and Services are not directed to, marketed towards or intended for children under thirteen (13) years of age and we request that children under 13 do not submit any personally identifiable information or any other information to our Site.

## Is My Personally Identifiable Information Secure?

The security of your personally identifiable information is important to Simple Green Smoothies. We use PayPal and WePay.com to process your purchases. The information is stored in an SSL encrypted database.

Please remember that no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic or physical storage is 100% secure. While we value the privacy and security of your personal information, we cannot guarantee against or prevent potential security breaches, nor can we assure you that the personally identifiable information that you provide us will never be disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

If you have reason to believe that the security of your information has been compromised, e-mail us immediately at [hello@simplegreensmoothies.com](mailto:hello@simplegreensmoothies.com).

## What Are My Opt Out Choices?

Electronic Newsletter and E-mail Communications

You may unsubscribe from our electronic newsletters or e-mail communications (including promotional e-mails) at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions in the e-mail or newsletter you received from us. You can also contact us via e-mail at [hello@simplegreensmoothies.com](mailto:hello@simplegreensmoothies.com).

###### VISITORS’ GDPR RIGHTS

If you are within the European Union, you are entitled to certain information and have certain rights under the General Data Protection Regulation. Those rights include:

We will retain the any information you choose to provide to us until the earlier of: (a) you asking us to delete the information, (b) our decision to cease using our existing data providers, or (c) the Company decides that the value in retaining the data is outweighed by the costs of retaining it.

You have the right to [request access](https://qk443.infusionsoft.com/app/form/web-form-submitted161) to your data that the Company stores and the rights to either rectify or erase your personal data.

You have the right to seek restrictions on the processing of your data.

You have the right to object to the processing of your data and the right to the portability of your data.

To the extent that you provided consent to the Company’s processing of your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based upon consent that occurred prior to your withdrawal of consent.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority that has jurisdiction over issues related to the General Data Protection Regulation.

We require only the information that is reasonably required to enter into a contract with you. We will not require you to provide consent for any unnecessary processing as a condition of entering into a contract with us.

## Correction or Deletion of Personally Identifiable Information

You may request that we update, change, correct, or delete your personally identifiable information at any time. If you request that we delete your personally identifiable information, we will remove your personally identifiable information that is stored in databases we actively use and in readily searchable formats. Please be aware, however, that it may not be technologically possible for us to erase or otherwise remove every record of the information you have provided to us, such as information stored on backup tapes or backup servers. We are not responsible for and cannot control the personally identifiable information that you have provided to third parties.

## California Residents

If you are a resident of California, you have the right to request a list of all third parties to which Simple Green Smoothies has disclosed certain personally identifiable information during the preceding year for third party direct marketing purposes. If you choose to make such a request, please be advised that you are limited to one request per calendar year. Please provide a current California address for our response to you and please also attest to the fact that you are a California resident. At this time, we only collect personally identifiable information about your online activities on our Site. We do not collect personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across third-party Web sites or online services.

## Does Simple Green Smoothies Use Affiliate Links?

Simple Green Smoothies is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com. We also use other affiliate programs and use affiliate referral links to third party sites, such as FourSigmatic and Nutiva. If you click on an affiliate link, please be sure to read that third party’s privacy policy to understand what happens to the personal information you submit to that third party. We do not have knowledge of or control over what happens to the personal information that you submit to third parties and are not responsible for those third parties’ disclosure or use of your personal information.

## How Will I Be Notified of Changes To The Privacy Policy?

We may change our Privacy Policy from time to time. When we make a material change to this Policy, we will post the changes on this Privacy Policy web page and may also inform you of the changes by other means, such as in our newsletter or in a direct e-mail containing the update.

## Questions About Our Privacy Policy?

Please direct any questions regarding this Privacy Policy via e-mail to [hello@simplegreensmoothies.com](mailto:hello@simplegreensmoothies.com) or in correspondence sent to our mailing address at P.O. Box 1261, Brooksville, FL 34605.
